- [Instructor] Zustand is another state management solution
with an atomic approach,
also inspired by Recoil.
It was developed by Jotai.
This lesson introduces you
to the Zustand State Management Library in React.
Zustand means state in German.
It is a lightweight and a simple state management solution
with an API based on hooks, similar to the React API.
So everything is going to feel very familiar,
comfortable and easy.
To create the store,
you're going to first import the method create
from the library Zustand.
Then we create a hook for the store
which is use bear store.
Then we define a state
with an initial state for the bears, which is set at zero.
And we also define functions
which are going to be used to carry over the data.
Then the state is bound to components.
We're going to import the hook in our components
and then bind the state to our components.
That's it.
This is a very simple data flow to manage it all.
So let's check it out with an example.
So in this sandbox we have a store.
So this one is named use store
and we define an initial state for the count
which is set at one, and we also have a function
that we're going to use to increment this value.
Then inside the functional component, we bound the state.
We bound the state to the store by calling use store,
which is our base hook store.
Then we can display the value of the count
to display the value of the counter
and also use inc,
which is the function that we use to increment the value
every time that you click on the button.
So why choose Zustand
over the Context API or Redux, for example?
Well, first it requires less boilerplate code.
Also, the data flow is very simple.
With a simple hook, the store hook can be used everywhere
from any components and no context provider is needed.
So that is many reasons to choose Zustand
as a state management solution.
In these sections, the project will build our (indistinct)
and a checklist for the challenge parts at the end.
So let's see how to use Zustand
as a state management solution.